<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michaël Aklin</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michaël Aklin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Heinz Foundation grant</title>
      <link>/news/2022-05-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2022-05-05/</guid>
      <description>May 5, 2022
The Heinz Foundation will generously fund a project on the barriers and opportunities faced by US fossil fuel workers in the midst of the clean energy transition. Green jobs could offer promising alternative livelihoods, but whether these jobs will meet people’s needs is uncertain. Where will these jobs materialize? How much reskilling will be required? Are these jobs competitive? And perhaps most importantly: do they meet people’s aspirations?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Research Impact on Practice Award</title>
      <link>/news/2021-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021-09-09/</guid>
      <description>September 9, 2021
My paper with Meital Rosenberg, Daniel Armanios, and Paulina Jaramillo has won the 2021 Research Impact on Practice Award established jointly by the Academy of Management and Network for Business Sustainability. The paper, titled “Evidence of gender inequality in energy use from a mixed-methods study in India,” is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News coverage of my paper with Mildenberger</title>
      <link>/news/2021-04-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021-04-21/</guid>
      <description>April 21, 2021
Over the last few weeks, the Atlantic (here), Bloomberg (here), the New York Times (here), and New York Magazine (here) all covered my recent work with Matto Mildenberger. Lot of interesting work and ideas developing in this area!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two papers out</title>
      <link>/news/2021-02-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021-02-13/</guid>
      <description>February 13, 2021
Two new papers came out in the last couple of weeks.
In the first, Kern, Negre, and I examine some of the side effects of central bank independence. We suspect that governments may respond to a loss of control over monetary policy (i.e. more independent central banks) with policies that are bad for inequality.
 Aklin, Michaël, Andreas Kern, and Mario Negre. 2021. Does Central Bank Independence Increase Inequality?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New article in Global Environmental Politics</title>
      <link>/news/2020-10-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020-10-29/</guid>
      <description>October 29, 2020
My paper with Matto Mildenberger, “Prisoners of the Wrong Dilemma: Why Distributive Conflict, Not Collective Action, Characterizes the Politics of Climate Change,” is out at Global Environmental Politics. You can find an ungated pre-print here.
Long story short: many argue that the main obstacle to effective climate policy is global free-riding. States are trapped in a prisoners’ dilemma, and we should put our effort into creating the kind of environment in which cooperation can be sustained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribune dans le Temps</title>
      <link>/news/2020-10-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020-10-20/</guid>
      <description>20 octobre 2020
J’ai publié une tribune sur la nouvelle loi suisse sur le CO2 dans Le Temps, disponible ici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New report with IISD</title>
      <link>/news/2020-10-06-iisd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020-10-06-iisd/</guid>
      <description>October 6, 2020
IISD just published a new report on electricity subsidies in India, with a focus on Jharkhand (written by Shruti Sharma, Tom Moerenhout, and myself). We show that electricity subsidies primarily benefit households that are wealthier. The report includes several alternative targetting options to ensure a more equal and just allocation of subsidies.
The report is available here: How to Target Residential Electricity Subsidies in India.
Some media coverage: Prabhat Khabar, Amar Ujala, DW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper in PNAS</title>
      <link>/news/2020-04-08-pnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020-04-08-pnas/</guid>
      <description>April 8, 2020
Patrick Bayer and I published a paper in PNAS (ungated) on the effectiveness of the European Union Emissions Trading Scheme (EU ETS). The EU ETS is one of the most ambitious attempts to put a price on carbon emissions. However, it has often been criticized as being too generous toward firms and therefore not having enough ‘bite.’ People often point at the ETS’ low permit prices as evidence for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Energy Policy Now podcast</title>
      <link>/news/2020-02-18-pennkleinman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020-02-18-pennkleinman/</guid>
      <description>My co-author Johannes Urpelainen and I chatted with Andy Stone who runs the Energy Policy Now podcast for the University of Pennsylvania’s Kleinman Center. You can listen to us talk about energy policy for the 2020s here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper in Nature Sustainability</title>
      <link>/news/2020-01-07-natsus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020-01-07-natsus/</guid>
      <description>Nature Sustainability recently published our article on energy access and gender inequality (co-authored by Meital Rosenberg, Daniel Armanios, Paulina Jaramillo, and I). The question is simple: once a household gets access to electricity, who benefits from it? Many studies in the past have shown that electricity access benefits women (for instance on the labor market). We show that things are not that straightforward when we examine its effect on households.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Marketplace</title>
      <link>/news/2019-11-18-npr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019-11-18-npr/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed by Marketplace on energy access and renewable energy in the world and in Sub-Saharan Africa. Interview available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two posts on off-grid electricity</title>
      <link>/news/2018-11-27-p4a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018-11-27-p4a/</guid>
      <description>I wrote two posts for Power for All. They draw on new data from IRENA on off-grid renewable electricity capacity in emerging and developing countries. In short, these data show (a) that capacity has increased substantially over the last 10 years, (b) not all developing countries benefitted from it, and (c) the most successful countries seem to be mid-income ones.
See here:
Middle-Income Countries Big Winner from Off-Grid Energy. Who’s Next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New book is out</title>
      <link>/news/2018-11-08-mit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018-11-08-mit/</guid>
      <description>Our book Escaping the Energy Poverty Trap (MIT Press), co-authored with Patrick Bayer, S.P. Harish, and Johannes Urpelainen, is now available in bookstores (MIT has links to several sellers; see here).
Here’s the blurb:
 The first comprehensive political science account of energy poverty, arguing that governments can improve energy access for their citizens through appropriate policy design.
  In today’s industrialized world, almost everything we do consumes energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication: How robust is the renewable energy industry to political shocks?</title>
      <link>/news/2018-10-04-bap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018-10-04-bap/</guid>
      <description>I just published a new article in Business and Politics called “How robust is the renewable energy industry to political shocks? Evidence from the 2016 U.S. elections.” Ungated link here.
The short version: the renewable energy industry has grown a lot since the 2000s. Its development was made possible by pro-active governments, who invested in R&amp;amp;D, set targets, etc. The logic is similar to the infant industry argument: in the presence of market failures, some sectors need public support to expand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type S and Type M errors in Stata: New .ado file</title>
      <link>/news/2018-09-15-stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018-09-15-stata/</guid>
      <description>P values are notoriously unreliable. We can quickly fell prey to statistically significant estimates. To overcome this, one approach has been to either abandon them altogether or require much harsher significance levels (Benjamin et al. 2018).
Another approach has been to use additional statistics to evaluate the reliability of our findings. If you want to stay in the hypothesis testing framework (and its coarse significant vs. non-significant results), then it is particularly important not to be mislead by a particular finding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New article in The Print</title>
      <link>/news/2018-09-13-theprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018-09-13-theprint/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a short article in The Print comparing electrification rates in India with its neighbors. In short: India has been doing well, but so has the region in general. As India gets closer to universal electrification (and we aren’t there yet, despite good progress), the focus needs to shift to improving quality of electricity provision. This will require to make the public and private industries operating in this area more sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
