<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy poverty on Michaël Aklin</title>
    <link>/tags/energy-poverty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Energy poverty on Michaël Aklin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/energy-poverty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021 Research Impact on Practice Award</title>
      <link>/news/2021-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2021-09-09/</guid>
      <description>September 9, 2021
My paper with Meital Rosenberg, Daniel Armanios, and Paulina Jaramillo has won the 2021 Research Impact on Practice Award established jointly by the Academy of Management and Network for Business Sustainability. The paper, titled “Evidence of gender inequality in energy use from a mixed-methods study in India,” is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper in Nature Sustainability</title>
      <link>/news/2020-01-07-natsus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020-01-07-natsus/</guid>
      <description>Nature Sustainability recently published our article on energy access and gender inequality (co-authored by Meital Rosenberg, Daniel Armanios, Paulina Jaramillo, and I). The question is simple: once a household gets access to electricity, who benefits from it? Many studies in the past have shown that electricity access benefits women (for instance on the labor market). We show that things are not that straightforward when we examine its effect on households.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Marketplace</title>
      <link>/news/2019-11-18-npr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2019-11-18-npr/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed by Marketplace on energy access and renewable energy in the world and in Sub-Saharan Africa. Interview available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two posts on off-grid electricity</title>
      <link>/news/2018-11-27-p4a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018-11-27-p4a/</guid>
      <description>I wrote two posts for Power for All. They draw on new data from IRENA on off-grid renewable electricity capacity in emerging and developing countries. In short, these data show (a) that capacity has increased substantially over the last 10 years, (b) not all developing countries benefitted from it, and (c) the most successful countries seem to be mid-income ones.
See here:
Middle-Income Countries Big Winner from Off-Grid Energy. Who’s Next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New book is out</title>
      <link>/news/2018-11-08-mit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2018-11-08-mit/</guid>
      <description>Our book Escaping the Energy Poverty Trap (MIT Press), co-authored with Patrick Bayer, S.P. Harish, and Johannes Urpelainen, is now available in bookstores (MIT has links to several sellers; see here).
Here’s the blurb:
 The first comprehensive political science account of energy poverty, arguing that governments can improve energy access for their citizens through appropriate policy design.
  In today’s industrialized world, almost everything we do consumes energy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
