<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michaël Aklin</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michaël Aklin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper in PNAS</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-08-pnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-08-pnas/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Bayer and I published a paper in [PNAS] (ungated) on the effectiveness of the European Union Emissions Trading Scheme (EU ETS). The EU ETS is one of the most ambitious attempts to put a price on carbon emissions. However, it has often been criticized as being too generous toward firms and therefore not having enough ‘bite.’ People often point at the ETS’ low permit prices as evidence for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Energy Policy Now podcast</title>
      <link>/post/2020-02-18-pennkleinman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-02-18-pennkleinman/</guid>
      <description>My co-author Johannes Urpelainen and I chatted with Andy Stone who runs the Energy Policy Now podcast for the University of Pennsylvania’s Kleinman Center. You can listen to us talk about energy policy for the 2020s here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New paper in Nature Sustainability</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-07-natsus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-07-natsus/</guid>
      <description>Nature Sustainability recently published our article on energy access and gender inequality (co-authored by Meital Rosenberg, Daniel Armanios, Paulina Jaramillo, and I). The question is simple: once a household gets access to electricity, who benefits from it? Many studies in the past have shown that electricity access benefits women (for instance on the labor market). We show that things are not that straightforward when we examine its effect on households.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Marketplace</title>
      <link>/post/2019-11-18-npr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-11-18-npr/</guid>
      <description>I was interviewed by Marketplace on energy access and renewable energy in the world and in Sub-Saharan Africa. Interview available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Content</title>
      <link>/post/rich-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rich-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo ships with several &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#use-hugo-s-built-in-shortcodes&#34;&gt;Built-in Shortcodes&lt;/a&gt; for rich content, along with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/&#34;&gt;Privacy Config&lt;/a&gt; and a set of Simple Shortcodes that enable static and no-JS versions of various social media embeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder Text</title>
      <link>/post/placeholder-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/placeholder-text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de
pectora summo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Typesetting</title>
      <link>/post/math-typesetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/math-typesetting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematical notation in a Hugo project can be enabled by using third party JavaScript libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emoji Support</title>
      <link>/post/emoji-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/emoji-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emoji can be enabled in a Hugo project in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two posts on off-grid electricity</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-27-p4a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-11-27-p4a/</guid>
      <description>I wrote two posts for Power for All. They draw on new data from IRENA on off-grid renewable electricity capacity in emerging and developing countries. In short, these data show (a) that capacity has increased substantially over the last 10 years, (b) not all developing countries benefitted from it, and (c) the most successful countries seem to be mid-income ones.
See here:
Middle-Income Countries Big Winner from Off-Grid Energy. Who’s Next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New book is out</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-08-mit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-11-08-mit/</guid>
      <description>Our book Escaping the Energy Poverty Trap (MIT Press), co-authored with Patrick Bayer, S.P. Harish, and Johannes Urpelainen, is now available in bookstores (MIT has links to several sellers; see here).
Here’s the blurb:
 The first comprehensive political science account of energy poverty, arguing that governments can improve energy access for their citizens through appropriate policy design.
  In today’s industrialized world, almost everything we do consumes energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication: How robust is the renewable energy industry to political shocks?</title>
      <link>/post/2018-10-04-bap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-10-04-bap/</guid>
      <description>I just published a new article in Business and Politics called “How robust is the renewable energy industry to political shocks? Evidence from the 2016 U.S. elections.” Ungated link here.
The short version: the renewable energy industry has grown a lot since the 2000s. Its development was made possible by pro-active governments, who invested in R&amp;amp;D, set targets, etc. The logic is similar to the infant industry argument: in the presence of market failures, some sectors need public support to expand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type S and Type M errors in Stata: New .ado file</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-15-stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-15-stata/</guid>
      <description>P values are notoriously unreliable. We can quickly fell prey to statistically significant estimates. To overcome this, one approach has been to either abandon them altogether or require much harsher significance levels (Benjamin et al. 2018).
Another approach has been to use additional statistics to evaluate the reliability of our findings. If you want to stay in the hypothesis testing framework (and its coarse significant vs. non-significant results), then it is particularly important not to be mislead by a particular finding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New article in The Print</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-13-theprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-13-theprint/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a short article in The Print comparing electrification rates in India with its neighbors. In short: India has been doing well, but so has the region in general. As India gets closer to universal electrification (and we aren’t there yet, despite good progress), the focus needs to shift to improving quality of electricity provision. This will require to make the public and private industries operating in this area more sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>